Jerome Rasky

jyrome.112@gmail.com (650) 394-5091 Vancouver, Canada

Overview

Rename

Former NASA Software Engineer with 5 years of professional work experience. Experience with systems programming and administration, front-end and back-end development, and project management.

Languages

Java • JavaScript • Go C++17 • C11 • Rust SQL • AMD64 Assembly

Frameworks

React • Redux • Webpack Android • WordPress • Django

Tools

Linux • Git • Emacs Bash • NodeJS • Mocha

Skills

Systems programming Site relability Backend development Frontend development

Education

The University of British Columbia

Vancouver, 2014-Present Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, graduating 2018

Coursework

Algorithms • Data Structures Operating Systems

Experience

New Relic

San Francisco, CA Summer 2016

Frontend engineer working on the newly-launched Infrastructure product. Made significant contributes, including on the backend and on other teams, which enabled the team to meet critical milestones.

Arrayent

Redwood City, CA Summer 2015

Site reliability engineer managing a large deployment of production systems. Resolved issues in services with real-time availability requirements, and learned to effectively monitor large-scale infrastructure.

NASA Ames

Mountain View, CA 2011-2014

Full-stack developer, managing both frontend and backend codebases and production systems. Worked closely with highly-specialized users to deliver interfaces to meet their needs the most closely.

UBC CS Student Society Vancouver, Fall 2016-Present Vice President External, responsible for the yearly Technical Career fair. Practiced effective communication to coordinate a diverse team in the organization of a complex event.

Personal Projects

Half2

Algorithms • Data Processing • Filesystems

B-tree implementation optimized nearly to match the one in the language. Started out as a version control system, but shifted to focus more directly on data structures.

Kernel

Systems • Algorithms • Memory Management

OS kernel research project, focusing on some ideas I have about operating systems. Prompted by a desire to learn more about operating systems and hardware.

BIS2/FLX Fuzzy Search • Optimized • Command-Line

Highly optimized fuzzy search for terminal history. Improves over the default search interface with better matching and a better UI. Has become something that I use every day as an integral part of my workflow.